What's up English adventurers are you ready to level up your grammar game today?
こんにちは、英語の冒険者たち。今日は文法をレベルアップする準備はできていますか？
We're going on an awesome quest to unlock a secret weapon in English the two infinitive. Let's do this
素晴らしい冒険に出かけて、英語の秘密兵器「不定詞」を解き明かします。さあ、始めましょう！
So get this did you know verbs are kind of like superheroes you think you know them
実は、動詞はスーパーヒーローのようなものなんです。知っていると思っていても、
But they have a secret identity a hidden power that lets you talk about all your dreams and hobbies in a brand new way
隠れた力を持っていて、夢や趣味について新しい方法で話すことができるんです。
I'm not kidding
本気ですよ。
Okay, so let's take a super simple verb play. We all know this one
では、超シンプルな動詞「play」を見てみましょう。みんな知っていますよね。
I play games. Easy-peasy, right? The verb is the action. It's what I'm doing. But, that's not the
「私はゲームをする。」簡単ですよね？動詞は行動を示しています。私がしていることです。でも、
whole story. But what if you want to talk about, you know, the idea of playing games, like the
それだけではありません。ゲームをするという「活動」について話したい場合はどうしますか？
activity itself? You can't just say, play games is fun. Ah, that sounds a little weird, doesn't it?
「ゲームをするのは楽しい」とは言えませんよね。ちょっと変に聞こえますよね？
To make it work, we need a little bit of English magic. And here it is. The magic spell is
うまくいかせるためには、少し英語の魔法が必要です。これがその魔法です。
the two infinitive. You probably know this as two futeishi in your classes. And it's so simple.
それが「不定詞」です。授業では「to不定詞」として知っているでしょう。とても簡単です。
You just stick the word two in front of a verb and bam, it's not an action anymore. It's a thing.
動詞の前に「to」を付けるだけで、行動ではなくなり、物事になります。
It becomes a noun that means the act of doing something. So check out the difference here.
それは「何かをする行為」を意味する名詞になります。ここでの違いを見てみましょう。
On the left, I play games. That's me doing an action. But on the right, to play games is fun.
左側は「私はゲームをする。」これは私の行動です。でも右側は「ゲームをするのは楽しい。」
See that? The whole idea of playing games. That is the thing that's fun. The verb just
見えますか？ゲームをするという全体のアイデアが楽しいのです。動詞は
just got a promotion. It's the star of the show now.
昇進しました。今や主役です。
All right, Graham requesters, your first power up is unlocked.
さて、文法の冒険者たち、最初のパワーアップが解放されました。
We're gonna master the subject skill
次は主語のスキルをマスターします。
where we make our new to infinitive
新しい不定詞を文の主役にします。
the main character of the sentence.
では、超簡単な文を見てみましょう。「科学は楽しい。」
Okay, let's look at a super easy sentence. Science is fun.
ここで、科学が主語ですね？
Here, science is the subject, right?
主なトピックで、シンプルです。さあ、見てください。
It's the main topic, nice and simple. Now watch this.
そして、私たちの新しいスーパーパワーを使って「科学を学ぶのは楽しい」と言います。
And bam, we use our new superpower to study science is fun.
何をしたか見えましたか？
Did you see what we did there?
「学ぶ」という行動を取り入れて、文全体の主役にしました。
We took the action, study, and turned it into the main character of the whole sense.
「科学を学ぶこと」が楽しいことになりました。
The act of studying science is now the thing that's fun.
そして、最も良い部分は、これをあなたが気に入っていることに何でも使えることです。
And here's the best part, you can use this for literally anything you care about.
「ビデオゲームをするのは私の好きな趣味。」私にとっては本当です。
To play video games is my favorite hobby. Totally true for me.
「アニメを見るのは素晴らしい。」
To watch anime is awesome.
その通りです。大きな夢についても話せます。
Heck yeah it is, or you can talk about your big dreams.
「有名なクリエイターになるのが私の夢。」素晴らしいですよね？レベルアップ！
To become a famous creator is my dream. So cool, right? Level up!
素晴らしい仕事をみんな！次はパワーアップ2、目的語のスキルです。
Awesome job everyone. Now for power-up number two, the object skill.
これが実際の会話で頻繁に使うものです。では、またシンプルに始めましょう。
And let me tell you, this is the one you're gonna use
「私はクッキーが好き。」誰が嫌いですか？
all the time in real conversations. Okay, let's start simple again.
「私」が主語、「好き」が動詞、「クッキー」が目的語です。
I like cookies. I mean, who doesn't?
私が好きなものです。今、温かい、
So I is the subject, like is the verb, and cookies is the object.
とろけるアメリカのチョコチップクッキーを思い浮かべています。
It's the thing I like. Hmm, I'm picturing a warm,
でも、ただ食べるのが好きなだけではなく、
gooey American chocolate chip cookie right now.
その行動が好きな場合はどうしますか？魔法の言葉を使いましょう。
Okay, but what if you don't just like eating them?
「私はクッキーを作るのが好き。」見えますか？
What if you like the action? Well, let's use our magic word.
今や「クッキーを作る」というフレーズが目的語です。
I like to make cookies, see?
それがあなたが好きな活動です。素晴らしいですね。
Now the whole phrase to make cookies is the object.
これを本当に上手にするためには、ボス動詞について知っておく必要があります。
It's the activity that you like, so cool.
彼らはビデオゲームの主役のようなもので、
Okay, to really get good at this,
常に特別なサイドキックを持っています。
you need to know about the boss verbs.
そのサイドキックが不定詞です。新しい仲間を紹介します。
Think of them like the main characters in a video game
「want」「like」「need」「decide」「begin」「start」「continue」。
and that sidekick is the two-infinitive. So here's your new crew.
これらの動詞はあなたの親友です。
Want, like, need, decide, begin, start, and continue.
これらのいずれかを使うときは、「次に不定詞が来るかも」と考えてください。
Whenever you use one of them, your brain should be thinking,
そして、素晴らしい文を作るレシピができました。
ooh, a two verb is probably coming next.
たった3つの簡単なステップです。ステップ1、人物を選ぶ、「私」。
Seriously, memorize these guys, they're super important.
ステップ2、ボス動詞を選ぶ、「want」。
And now you have the recipe for an awesome sentence.
ステップ3、動作を「to」で加える、「ハリウッドを訪れる」。
It's just three easy steps. Step one, pick a person, I.
はい、「私はハリウッドを訪れたい。」
Step two, pick a boss verb, want.
または「彼女はアメリカのハンバーガーを試すことに決めた。」
See, you can make endless sentences just like this.
ほら、こんな風に無限に文を作れるんだ。
And there you have it, quest complete.
これでクエスト完了だね。
You've unlocked the two major skills of the two infinitive.
二つの不定詞の主要なスキルを手に入れたよ。
But this isn't just about passing a grammar test.
でも、これは単なる文法テストのためじゃない。
This is about unlocking a real superpower.
これは本当のスーパーパワーを手に入れることなんだ。
Because this is what it's all about.
これが全ての要点だよ。
This isn't just some boring rule from a textbook. It's a key.
これは教科書の退屈なルールじゃなくて、鍵なんだ。
It's the key that lets you tell people about your hopes,
あなたの希望や、
your dreams, what you're passionate about.
夢、情熱について人に伝えるための鍵だ。
It's how you express who you really are.
自分を表現する方法なんだ。
So what did you win on this quest? The power of expression.
このクエストで何を手に入れたかって？表現力だよ。
Now you can actually say things like, I want to be a YouTuber, or I decided to join the
今なら「YouTuberになりたい」とか「サッカーチームに入ることにした」とか、
soccer team, or I need to study for the test.
「テストのために勉強しなきゃ」と言えるようになった。
Your English communication skills just got a huge boost.
あなたの英語コミュニケーション能力が大きく向上したよ。
So my final challenge to you is this. You've got this new superpower.
だから、最後の挑戦はこれだ。新しいスーパーパワーを手に入れたんだ。
What's the very first thing you want to say with it?
最初に何を言いたい？
What's your dream? What's your goal? Go on.
あなたの夢は？目標は？さあ、言ってみて。
Try making a sentence right now. You guys were awesome today.
今すぐ文を作ってみて。今日は素晴らしかったよ。
Great work.
素晴らしい仕事だ。